



Summary

I am a developer and system analyst with a wide experience in networking and web development. Technology maintains continuously evolving, so I am always trying to do the same. Being a firm believer of that, my primary goal through my entire career is to never stay in the same role, using the same tools and technology, but to use my own self-driven attitude to keep up and embrace new and effective ways to achieve the goals to complete and make projects work in the best way possible.

During my career I've had and particularly enjoyed hands-on experiences with concepts like Clustering, Membrane Computing and with the use of social APIs for "Social Insight" and "Social Data Mining". Currently I have been assigned in leading roles, handling development areas designing the fittest solutions for clients, being responsible for managing teams in the most effective way to harness their potential. As a leader, I am always trying to identify my

team's strengths so they can work in the most efficient way possible. I really enjoy helping them discover their own career path.



Work History

2022-10 -Current

Lead Tech

Morgan Stanley, Mexico City

- Updated services applications from Angular 10 to Angular 13
- Improved webpacking time
- Improved mobile applications packaging time



Address

01020, Mexico City CMX

Phone

553-132-9293

E-mail

ramiroalves@gmail.com



Scrum Master



Management tools (Jira, git, harvest, code quality auditing tools, ...)



Azure, AWS, and custom manteinance and server's service management.



Javascript/Typescript



Node.js Frameworks (Express, Sails, Loopback).



C# and .NET Framework overall (WCF, WPF, ASP.net, others)



Angular



React



Vue



Python



2021-12 -2022-10 Senior Fullstack Developer

Condenast

 Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.

- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- Developed unit test cases for testing and automation.
- Participated in requirements gathering to solidify prerequisites and determine best technical solution to meet business needs.
- Provided software application engineering and maintenance for development lifecycle.
- Coordinated efficient large-scale software deployments.
- Conceptualized, designed, and delivered access matrix and restricted content BackOffice's for previewing content on multiple CondeNast platform's

2021-02 -2022-01 Back-End Leader

The Brane

- Data modeling for The Brane Application
- Leading role in Topics Api for The Brane Application

2019-01 -2021-12 Full-Stack Senior Developer Rightsource

- Lead developer for PresencePG on Makena Capital's investment site using Node, MySQL and React. Also developed experience using Addepar accounting APIs for telemetric retrieval of financial data.
- Lead developer on FTP-to-AWS inner hub: Created critical bridge tool on

SQL and NoSQL handling.



RESTful & GraphQL

- high-level security internal documents to be provided by a third party using Encryption and AWS Lambda.
- Fullstack developer for BusinessWire: Upgrading legacy services on BusinessWire press release's application.
- Fullstack developer for BorregoSolar: Development on Financial Modeling and Polling States for Solar Panels.
- Fullstack developer for General Motors: Development for microservices in Lending Electric Energy from Car2Car future application.

2020-05 -2021-09

Back-End Leader

Grupo Umvel

- Mobile and Desktop structure leader on
 VivaAerobus site to be released in 2021 (Angular
 9): Modularizing components for reusing
 components, pipes, and behavior on mobile and
 desktop versions.
- Architect on interconnection between legacy services on Seguros Mundial (C#, SOAP, NodeJs): Interconnecting existing services with new client platform based on NodeJS and Angular 9.
- Front-end leader on Miyana's Food Central
 application to be released in 2021: Definition and
 building based on client feedback admin's
 dashboard to handle restaurants, orders,
 deliveries, payments and usage stats on Angular
 9.
- Back-end architect for Bimbo Exercise Goals app:
 Defining interconnection and behavior between backend structured in ExpressJs and communicating to AWS Cognito, Aurora, S3, SQS and Lambda.
- Lead Back-end for BDV Solutions 2.0:
 Interconnecting courier services like FEDEX,
 document signing and providing api's based on
 Nest and GraphQL with Mongoose.
- Personal goals accomplished:

- Implemented code standards for clean code philosophy for the back-end team.
- Implemented git flows and base template for NodeJs new projects.
- Implemented weekly grooming crash courses on team deficiencies to level employees getting behind.

2019-12 -2021-09

Tech Leader

Garage Coders

- Front-end Lead dev on DERI Puebla's site (Local Police's crime tracker): Leaded front-end's team on building police's crime tracker built on Angular using AWS SQS.
- Front-end Lead dev on ShouldCost's site
 (Construction's scaffolder): Built design-based a
 budget calculator system for ShouldCost'
 company as their main tool used to present to
 their clients. Built on Django and Angular 8.
- Front-end dev on Laundry Service App Wosh: Built stats section for Wosh, laundry system used in Spain as a competitor to Mr Jeff.
- Architect on multicourier shipping tool:
 Implemented architecture and services
 communicating with FEDEX, Stafeta,
 WooCommerce, Shopify and Redpack with Paket and Punto Activo's backend (NodeJs).

2016-07 -2019-06

Senior Full-Stack Developer

IDALO, LLC

- Front-end Lead for sky52: Initially with Django, moved to Laravel, participated as a fullstack developer on incident's handling for skiing resorts on china, was on of my first experiences as a freelancer.
- Lead developer for MAPGrip: Tool built on VueJS and Laravel providing a backend and a website as a way to visit points of interest in Tasmania.
 Backend service was also providing information for AR applications.

Web Developer

Globant

 Front-end developer for Morgan Stanley: Built Send Money With Zelle Module for Morgan Stanley's using Angular and Cordova, more details covered by NDA.

2014-02 -2017-11

Senior Backend Developer

3rd Party Confidential Company

May 2015 - Actual

- Back-End Endpoint developer for "Surveillance Web System" for a private stakeholder.
- Technologies: Node.js, angular-fullstack.
- Tools: Webstorm, CouchDB.

May 2015 - Actual

- Back-End Cloud Azure developer for "Surveillance Web System" for a private stakeholder.
- Technologies: Node.js, Angular-fullstack, Azure library.
- Additional comments: Telemetry and queue Azure implementations to achieve real-time communication between multiple devices.

May 2015 - Actual

- Back-End security developer for "Surveillance Web System" for a private stakeholder.
- Technologies: Node.js, CouchDB, OAuth 2.0.
- Additional comments: Custom implementation OAuth 2.0 (RFC 6749) for the whole project.

May 2015 - Actual

- Front-End developer and Front-End UX/UI QAs for "Surveillance Web System" for a private stakeholder.
- Technologies: Angular.js, Angular-fullstack, several other component libraries.

November 2014 - April 2015

- Front-end C# development for "Expenditure" for a private stakeholder.
- Technologies: MVVM, .NET Framework 3.5.
- Tools: Visual Studio 2013.

February 2014 - October 2014

- Back-end C# development for "Technicians Handheld" for a private stakeholder.

- Technologies involved: .NET Identity 2.0, .NET Web API 2.2, .NET Entity Framework 6.0, OAuth 2.0, x.509 propietary implementation.
- Tools: Couchbase, Couchbase .NET Library, Visual Studio 2013.

June 2012 - January 2014

 Private development in computer security area for a third-party stakeholder.

2009-02 -2012-05

Junior Developer

Xpectra, C.A.

- IDE Development for transaction type developments for XCOPE's final product -Internship.
- Design and Development of NetMATRIX's (Telemanagement software) Indicator and event Viewer. - Internship.
- Proposal of Visual paradigm for the design of NetMATRIX 2012 Interfaces.

2008-02 -2011-06

Computing Lab Operator

Universidad Católica Andrés Bello - Guayana

Manager in charge of the proper functioning and correct use of the CPUs and several Computer Labs on campus.

2009-09 -2010-06

Volunteer

Universidad Católica Andrés Bello

Design, development, publishing, and technological transfer of Fe y Alegría's educational software "Peace's Path".



Education

2006-03 -2011-05

Computer Scientist On Universidad Católica Andrés Bello. - Puerto Ordaz

Activities and Societies:

- English Conversational Club.
- Computing-Lab Operator.
- Practical teaching for Algorithms and

Programming III.

Optatives:

- Emergent Computing
- Programmable Logic Controllers (PLC).
- Web Development.
- Database Management.